Saratoga Springs Open Space Project; Records apap155
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Trails, 1986-2000; Undated; 4; 1.33 cubic ft.
  - "City Opens Space Committee shapes proposed bike route"The Saratogian, 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 90)
  - Canoe Trial Day, Flier, 1995 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 91)
  - Recreational needs committee, Correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 92)
- Subject Files, 1973-1976; 1980-1982; 1987-2003; Undated; 5; 3.66 cubic ft.
  This series contains subject files about various environmental, historical, and preservation topics affecting the Saratoga Springs region. These files were collected by Barbara Glaser in a separate filing cabinet and have a slightly broader range of subjects than the files in the Programs and Issues series. Nevertheless, there is a great deal of overlap and most of the topics can be found in both series, with this series mainly consisting of News Clippings and the Programs and Issues series having a more diverse assortment of materials. There may well have been some intermingling between the contents of these filing cabinets, as some of the files in this series, particularly those from The Next Steps & Beyond program, would seem to fit better in the Programs and Issues series.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Adams Road, Correspondence, Petition for Zoning Amendment, 1997 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - "Adopt A Highway", 1996; 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Agriculture and Farmland Protection Program Circular, 1992 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - American Farmland Trust, Newspaper Clipping, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Amtrak, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, 1998-1999; Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Archeology, High Rock, Newspaper Clipping, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Archeology Study, Maple Avenue, Newspaper Clipping, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Awards, Newspaper Clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Bog Meadow Creek Trail, Disturbance Permit, 1995 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Bond Act, Newspaper Clippings, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Borders, Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Broadway Post Office, Newspaper Clippings, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Canalway Trail, Friends of Canalway Trail, Meeting Minutes, Notes, Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Canalway Trail, Publications, Maps, 1996-1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Casion Gambling, Newspaper Clippings, 1995-1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Cell Towers, Newspaper Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Chamber of Commerce, Newspaper Clippings, 1995-1997; 1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Championing New York's Parks, Participant List, Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Champlain Trail, Newspaper Clipping, Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - City Council, Newspaper Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - City Entrances, Newspaper Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Cleanup, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, 1996; 1998-2000 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Community Supported Agriculture, Newspaper Clipping, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Congress Park, Newspaper Clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Congress Park Center, Master Plan, Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Democrats, Newspaper Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Disabilities, Newspaper Clippings, 1996; 1998-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Diversity, Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Downtown, Newspaper Clippings, 1995-1997 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Downtown, Newspaper Clippings, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Downtown, Newspaper Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Downtown Historical District Design Guideline, 1997 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Downtown Issues, Broadway Mini-Mall, Newspaper Clippings, 1992; 1992-1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Downtown Issues, Chruch Street Marketplace, Burlington, Vermont, Publications, Fliers, 1995 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Downtown Pedestrian Improvement Plan, Plan, Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Downtown Steering Committee, Articles, 1993-1995 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Downtown Steering Committee, Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, Notes, Reports, 1995; Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - East of Northway Development, Newspaper Clippings, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Economic Development, Newspaper Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Education & Youth Activities, Environmental Education, 1994-1996 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Education & Youth Activities, Newspaper Clippings, 1995-1997; 1999-2000 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Education & Youth Activities, Trail Mapping Program, Class Materials, Maps, Newspaper Clippings, 1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Excelsior Avenue Ice Rink, Newspaper Clippings, 2000 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Exit 14, Correspondence, Memoranda, Photographs, 1994 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Exit 14, Letters to the Editor, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Exit 14, Newspaper Clippings, 1991; 1993-February 1994 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Exit 14, Newspaper Clippings, 1994 March-1994 May (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Elderly, Newspaper Clippings, 1997; 2000 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Farms, Newspaper Clippings, 1992; 1994-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Farmers Market, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Friends of Saratoga Spa State Park, 1995; 1997-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Greentree Estate, Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Hiss, Tony, Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Historical Society, Newspaper Clippings, Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Historic Preservation, Newspaper Clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Home Depot, Correspondence, Notes, Publications, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Home Depot, News Clippings, 1997 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Home Depot, News Clippings, 1998 January-1998 February (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Home Depot, News Clippings, 1998 March-1998 April (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Home Depot, News Clippings, May 1998-1999 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Home Depot, Slides, Bumper sticker, Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Hudson River, News Clippings, 1997; 1999-2000 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Hunter's Hollow, News Clippings, 1998 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Karner Blues, 1992-1995 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Kayaderosseras Creek, 1994; 1996-1997; 2000; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Kayaderosseras Creek, Maps, Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Kunstler, Jim, News Clippings, 1995-1998 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Lake Access, Legislation Notes, 1995-2000 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Lake Lonely, 1996-2000 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Land Acquisition, Anderson Land Donation, Maps, Deeds, 1997 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Land Acquisition, Aronson Land, Notes, Map, Correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Land Acquisition, Bowersox Project, Maps, Notes, 1997; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Land Acquisition, Larkin Parcel, Maps, 1998 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Land Acquisition, McNeary Land, Correspondence, 1997 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Land Acquisition, Notes, News Clippings, Maps, 1993; 1998; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Land Acquisition, Vernon Land Donation, Map, Deed, 1995 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Land Acquisition, William Moore Land Donation, Maps, Correspondence, News Clippings, 1997; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Land Trusts, News Clippings, 1999; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Landfill, News Clippings, 1998-2000 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Library, News Clippings, 1995; 1998; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Lillian's Parking Lot Pocket Park, Notes, Photographs, 2003; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Local Resources, Brochures, Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Main Street Revival, 1993-1995 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Marion Avenue Planned Unit Development, Correspondence, Position Papers, Maps, 1994; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - New York Main Street Alliance, Newsletters, Correspondence, Pamphlets, 1995; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - The Next Steps & Beyond, Broadway Mini-Mall, Ad-Hoc Committee, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - The Next Steps & Beyond, Correspondence, Reports, 1990; 1994-1995; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - The Next Steps & Beyond, Downtown Community Forum for Young People, 1994 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - The Next Steps & Beyond, Events, 1994-1995; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - The Next Steps & Beyond, News Clippings, 1993-1995 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - The Next Steps & Beyond, Sign-in and Mailing Lists, Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - The Next Steps & Beyond, Suggestions and Ideas, Notes, Correspondence, 1994; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - The Next Steps & Beyond, Swift and Simple Victories, Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Niagara Mohawk site, News Clippings, Flyers, 1995; 1997-1999; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Nonprofits, News Clippings, 1998 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Northway, News Clippings, 1997; 2000 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Open Space, News Clippings, 1995-2000 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Open Space Plan, 1989-1991; 1994; 1999-2000; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Open Space Project, News Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Park and Ride Lot, Correspondence, Maps, 1996-1997 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Parking, News Clippings, report, 1997-2000 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Parks, Milton Moreau, News Clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Peripheral Development Forum, 1994-1995; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Petrified Sea Garden, 1976; 1980-1981; 1989-1991; 1996; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Planning Board, News Clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Project for Public Spaces, Proposal, 1994 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Property Information, 1998-2000; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Property Transactions, News Clippings, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Public Safety, News Clippings, 1993-1999; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Rails to Trails, News Clippings, 1987; 1997-2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Recreation Department, News Clippings, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Recycling, News Clippings, Flyer, 1997; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Regionalization, News Clippings, 1997 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Resources, Address List, Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Review of 1997, News Clippings (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Rip Van Dam Hotel, News Clippings, 1996-2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Route 50, News Clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Saratoga Bikeway Advisory Committee, 1994-1997; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Saratoga Bikeway Advisory Committee, Maps, 1996 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Saratoga Bikeway Advisory Committee, 1993-1997 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Saratoga County, News Clippings, 1995-1998 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Saratoga County Options for Independent Living, News Clippings, 1996 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Saratoga County Twenty-first Century Study Commission, Report, 1987 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Saratoga County Historic Trail Committee, Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Saratoga County Historic Trail Committee, Maps, Minutes, Notes, Correspondence, 1995 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Saratoga County Historic Trail Committee, Meetings, Minutes, Agendas, Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Saratoga County Historic Trail Committee, Publications, 1994-1995 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Saratoga County Historic Trail Committee, Resolutions, By-laws, Certificate of Incorporation, 1992-1993; 1997 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Saratoga County Water Quality Committee, 2002-2003 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Saratoga Film Forum, News Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Saratoga Foundation, News Clippings, 1995; 1997-1998 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Saratoga Lake, 1992; 1996-2000; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Saratoga Spa State Park, 1995-1997 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Saratoga Spa State Park, 1998-2000; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Saratoga Springs City Government, News Clippings, 1991-1992; 1995-1997 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Saratoga Springs City Government, News Clippings, 1998-2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Saratoga Springs Master Plan, News Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Saratoga Springs Plan of Action, 1973 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Saratoga Springs Plan of Action, 1974 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Scottsdale, 1995; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Senior Citizens, News Clippings, 1998 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - "A Sense Of Place", Historical Society of Saratoga Springs, Flier, Leaflet, 1995 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Shelters at Saratoga, News Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Skidmore, News Clippings, 1995-1998 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Smart City, Task Force Handbook, News Clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - South Broadway, News Clippings, 1997-2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - SPAHA, News Clippings, Pamphlets, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Special Access District, News Clippings, 1998 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Special Assessment District Law, 1996 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Sprawl, News Clippings, 1995; 1999-2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Spring run trial, News Clippings, Correspondence, 1992; 1997-2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - State Government, News Clippings, 1995-1997 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Tax Exempt Policy, News Clippings, 1998 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Teens, News Clippings, 1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Teens, Sidewalk Issues, News Clippings, 1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Tourism, News Clippings, 1998 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Truck Bypass, Correspondence, 1988; 1996; 2000; Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Truck Bypass, Correspondence, Emily Muller, 1996 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Truck Bypass, Maps, Diagrams, Undated (Box 4 (5-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Truck Bypass, Minutes, Notes, Fact Sheets, 1996; Undated (Box 4 (5-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Truck Bypass, News Clippings, 1987-1988; 1994-1995 (Box 4 (5-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Truck Bypass, News Clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 4 (5-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Truck Bypass, News Clippings, 1998-2000 (Box 4 (5-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Truck Bypass, Presentation to Open Space Project by Lew Bonton, Maps, 1994 (Box 4 (5-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Truck Bypass, Reports, 1977; 1987-1988; 1994; 1996 (Box 4 (5-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Truck Bypass, "Undiscovered Park" Art Exhibition, 1996; Undated (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Van Raalte Mill, News Clippings, Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Water Authority, News Clippings, 1995; 1997; 1999 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Water Issues, News Clippings, 1994; 1997; 1999-2000 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Water's Edge, News Clippings, 1994; 1997-1998 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Westside, News Clippings, Publications, 1996-2000 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Wetlands, News Clippings, 1996-2000 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Wildlife, News Clippings, 1997-2000 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Wilton Issues, News Clippings, 1996-2000 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Yaddo Artists Community, News Clippings, Newsletter, 1999 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Zoning Board, News Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Zoning Ordinance, 1999 (Box 5 (5-Subject Files), Folder 12)